What are red flags that you see that you
know could be applied to retail
investors? Potentially like really low
float like uh the founding team or core
team owning a really large percentage of
an asset bug within like the smart
contract itself. Potential nefarious
kind of market makers associated with
this project. The government can
actually buy and sell these crypto
altcoins. It just sounds like there's
this huge whale that can buy and trade
these altcoins. But how does that affect
the overall project? I don't think we
are going to have a great Q3 and Q4. I'm
very optimistic.
One of the world's largest. We're
speaking now with Marshall Beard. He is
the chief operating officer of Gemini,
one of the world's largest exchanges.
We'll be talking about the future of not
just crypto exchanges, but also the
future of Gemini. Welcome to the show,
Marshall. I'm David Lynn. I'm Bonnie.
Good to see you, Marshall. Thank you for
having me. The US is now more pro-
crypto. That is of course the opinion of
market observance. First of all, do you
agree with this overall viewpoint given
what Trump's done so far three months
into his term? And second, if it is a
more crypto friendly regulator, you
know, environment, what does this mean
for exchanges?
I absolutely agree with that sentiment.
Um, you can just see it. um you know a
year ago conversations were much
different than today and the industry
here in the US faced um you know pretty
massive headwinds and now we face pretty
massive tailwind so it's been incredible
very optimistic it's very exciting you
see pro crypto uh picks within uh the
treasury within the SEC within the CFTC
we have a you know digital assets
working group with uh David Sachs and so
you know everything that you know Trump
campaigned on is he's delivered. Uh so
it's incredibly exciting what it means
for the industry, what it means for our
business. Um you know it's it's you know
it helps us kind of find the clarity
that we've been looking for that we that
we didn't get in the last
administration. Uh right now there's two
bills being proposed. One is around
stablecoin bill, one's around a market
structure bill. Those are the first
steps that are going to really kind of
solidify how to operate here in the US
and I think global regulators will also
look at that too. So it's very exciting.
We're very optimistic and uh couldn't
kind of be going better. I think it
creates more competition in the space,
right? Presumably the mode is being
removed
potentially. I mean, it depends on how
you think about regulatory mode and the
competitive advantage of that. I think
there's going to be some operators that
still maybe, you know, cannot operate
under a rule setting regardless of of
where it is. So, uh, we welcome more
growth and opportunity and so we haven't
really been thinking about regulatory
capture uh, with this change at all.
What are exchanges doing in light of new
ETFs being launched? You know, they're
not coins on an exchange. Are there
compet competing product? I don't think
they compete. You know, when the ETFs
launched last year, started with
Bitcoin, now we have an Ethereum ETF.
There's applications for other uh, token
ETFs. uh you know one side of that is
you know all these ETF issuers need a
custodian. So Gemini is actually a
custodian for um some of the largest
ETFs in the world uh in multiple
countries. Gemini has a little over 20
billion of crypto under management. Um
so you know we end up working with ETF
issuers anyways uh through our
custodianship. They also then
potentially trade uh settle and clear
through the platform as well. Um, I
think
it's I think it's additive to our
business. I think it's additive to the
industry. It's a different type of
investor that might be buying these
ETFs. It might be a different type of
institutional investor or a different
type of consumer that invests in this,
but you know, you're not getting 24/7
access. You're not being able to do
anything on chain with this. So, it's a
different product so to say, but I think
it's additive.
Um, you talk about custody. So, I want
to ask you about insurance. How does it
work in crypto world today if you can
comment on it? Insurance. Yeah. Um, some
custodians offer or exchanges and
custodians offer insurance. Um, some
don't, I would assume. Gemini, uh, Trust
Company, which is our New York uh,
Department of Financial Services
regulated qualified custodian. Uh, we do
have digital asset insurance. Uh,
upwards of nine figures of insurance on,
I think it's called species insurance,
uh, for, you know, um, uh, hacks or or
fraud or something. So if premiums are
still pretty expensive um and not
everyone has insurance, we have some
insurance on our qualified custodian. I
asked this because of the recent hack of
in other exchange. It was the biggest
hack of human history, right? So how
could that be prevented in your view?
Yeah, what happened with that hack is I
can only see what I can see publicly.
And so, you know, when I see publicly,
our security team did kind of an
analysis. Our uh crypto infrastructure,
our wallet and key management
infrastructure is built differently. Our
custodian is proprietarily built in
house. Um I think they had a partner
that was involved. And so I can't speak
too fluently on what happened there. Um
other than you know, we did a review.
what happened to them does not impact
our custodianship. I think you know what
we do best at Gemini is keep digital
assets safe. It's what we've done for
the last decade. Uh we'll continue to do
that.
Are you in Asia? We are. Uh Gemini's
Asian headquarters is in Singapore. I
think we have I don't know 60 employees
in Singapore. Um they manage kind of all
of our operations in the region. Okay.
And that is your main um country in
Asia. Correct. Yeah, we have an
inprincipal approval license with the
monetary authority of Singapore and
Singapore itself uh is one of our you
know top uh uh jurisdictions. Okay. Are
you expanding to any other Asian
countries? Yeah, so we operate in in
other Asian countries. Uh we have a
focus on Southeast Asia. Um you know we
look at you know we look at regulation
that Hong Kong passes. We look at you
know JFSA in Japan. uh we look at South
Korean rags you know and then maybe even
outside of Southeast Asia with Australia
and Turkey where there's great adoption
so we look at you know territory as a
whole and you know if it makes sense
within the thesis of growth we we can
you know uh operate there what is your
edge how do you compete with other local
exchanges sure um you know Gemini has
incredible product suite right so you
know we are customer obsessed we offer
simple easy to use uh onboarding and
getting into crypto for, you know,
newcomers and we offer institutional
grade, you know, protail um features as
well. So, we service everybody. We have
elegant products. Uh we have incredible
fiat rail, so we make it really easy to
be the bridge from, you know,
traditional dollars into crypto. Um, and
you know, we've been doing this for a
long time. We've been doing this for
over a decade. We have a strong brand
and great products. People people love
using Gemini. And you do have
derivatives, right? Correct. Yes. What's
your uh listings uh decision-m process?
Sure. Um we have um you know uh
historically and still today we have a
pretty rigorous listing process. Gemini
does not uh have um you know as many
coins as some of our competitors um kind
of purposefully uh strategically and so
we have internal committees um we have
regulators globally that have uh listing
frameworks as well. We follow that uh we
get board approval um you know our
security teams, our risk teams, our
fraud teams is a very comprehensive
review of a new token that goes all the
way up to our board uh for every token
that gets listed on Gemini.
Well, that is interesting because other
exchanges, for example, some exchanges
in Asia, the listing happens in half a
day. Like a coin could come out in the
morning and it's on the exchange by
noon. We can move very quickly tech like
technically, you know, we can operate
very quickly to list new tokens, but we
just have a rigorous process to allow
customers access to those coins within
our product. reasoning
uh safety uh security soundness. We want
to review uh the contract code. Uh we
want to review who who who launched it,
the founders potentially. Um we want to
look at you know um if customers are
demanding it, all sorts of different
reasons. So you're not chasing the hype
so-called not particularly.
What are red flags that you see that you
know could be applied to retail
investors?
Can you elaborate on that? Red flags and
projects that you may see that you would
hesitate on listing and you know some
lessons you learned there that we can
learn from potentially like really low
float like uh the founding team or core
team owning a really large percentage of
an asset. Um some sort of um uh bug
within like the smart contract itself.
Um you know uh potential nefarious kind
of market makers associated with a
project, things like that. I don't know.
of the founders important for you
something look at look uh Bitcoin
doesn't have a known founder um and so
it's a it's just a piece of our
framework that we look at we do a risk
assessment on many different things
uh last question for me so can you
comment on some of the kinds of coins
that are most popular right now by
trading volume on Gemini yes crypto is
very interesting and you know phases
come and go I think you know in the last
few months, memecoins had this like uh
big adoption rate and large volatility.
I think that's actually quieted down
over the last few weeks, which is
interesting. It was kind of short-lived.
Um but, you know, as new layer 2s come
out, as new stable coins come out, as
kind of meme coins come out or community
tokens come out. Um you know, we look at
all those for listing on Gemini, but um
it kind of comes in uh in waves.
Question about the um crypto stockpile.
Why do you think they pick these coins?
Yeah, I think right now they've only
committed for the strategic reserve to
be Bitcoin, which I think is probably
the right way to start. Um, how they
look at tokens after that, you know,
similar to how we look at utility of
tokens at Gemini, right? Uh, what is the
value it creates, how many people are
using this thing, what is the utility
behind it, what is the market cap, what
is the velocity, what, you know, how
many developers are building on the
chain. Uh you I' I would look at that if
I was in charge of the reserves. So it's
not because it's made in the USA. Oh.
Oh, that might be a component, too. Hard
to tell sometimes what is made in the
USA verse not within crypto. So, um
that's definitely a factor I think they
look at. I do have a question though.
So, it says the government can actually
buy and sell these crypto altcoins. Um
how does that affect these altcoins?
They're just well to me it just sounds
like there's this huge whale that can
buy and trade these altcoins. But how
does that affect the overall project? I
don't think the US government is going
to be actively trading tokens, right? I
think they're going to actively uh
acquire through various mechanisms. They
might dispose of assets for certain
reasons. Uh but I don't think they're
going to be trading. I you know for
bitcoin it's positive obviously price
you know currently hasn't like done much
with that announcement which is you know
fine generally and then for altcoins I
mean if it gets announced and they have
low market caps it's probably a bullish
you know indicator for it but I don't
think there's been any commitments to
altcoins yet. Are you able to comment on
why do we have all these great news but
the price isn't that great? Yeah, crypto
currently at least right now is tied to
broader macro. The new administration uh
President Trump, you know, has created
friction and uncertainty in the markets
through uh the speed at which he's
operating right now. I'm not too
concerned about this long term at all. I
think this is initial uncertainty of how
he's going to, you know, run his
administration. Um but I've been doing
crypto for a long time. This is this is
nothing. A short-term bump. Correct.
Define short term
first half of the year. Okay. So, we are
going to have a great Q3 and Q4. I'm
very optimistic. That's great news. It's
a moving interview making me cry.
Thank you so much, Marshall. Of course.
Thank you. Appreciate you coming out.
Absolutely. Thank you. Great to meet
you. That was great. Thank you. Awesome.
Thank you. It was here to meet you.